CHRISTIAN ANDERSON, MBA

FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER

CONTACT

christian.p.anderson1@gmail.com 303-946-5386

LINKEDIN

linkedin.com/in/christian-p-anderson

PORTFOLIO

andersonchristian-p.github.io

GITHUB

github.com/AndersonChristian-P

LOCATION

Denver, CO (willing to relocate)

CERTIFICATIONS

Certified ScrumMaster (CSM) Scrum Alliance Issued Jul 2019 - Expires Jun 2021

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- JavaScript / ES6 SQL
- HTML5
- Git
- CSS3
- Agile
- ReactJS
- MS Office
- Node

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development DevMountain 2019

MBA

University of Alaska Anchorage 1998 - 2002

Bachelor's – Biological Sciences University of Alaska Fairbanks 1992 - 1997

SUMMARY

Front-End Web Developer with expertise in modern tech stack. **UI / UX web design award** recognition. MBA / Scrum Master certified. Over 18 years of professional experience working collaboratively in teams. Deep interest in efficiency, team building, communication, and work ethics.

DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

DevMountain - Web Developer

2019

Brodium | brodium.dtour.world

Workplace communication platform that brings in customer reviews as context for discussion.

- HTML5, Sass, CSS3, JavaScript, Axios, ReactJS, and Redux for the stylings and functionality on the front-end.
- Node, Express, Massive, SQL for handling requests and database for the backend. BcryptJS for authentication.
- Built RESTful APIs in JavaScript and Express.
- **NodeMailer** to initiate team-member onboarding process via email. Chat rooms created using **Socket.io**. **Cron** was utilized to query Google Places for business reviews once a day.
- Amazon S3 to host user profile images.
- Cypress for end-to-end testing. Jest for unit testing.
- The entire application was built using React hooks.

DevMountain - Web Developer

2019

Hiut Clone | hiut-clone.happycoder.io

Cloned the major features of <u>Hiut Denim's eCommerce site</u> to learn how to apply the technology to an eCommerce platform.

- HTML5, Sass, CSS3, JavaScript, Axios, ReactJS, Redux, Stripe for the stylings and functionality on the front-end.
- Node, Express, Massive, SQL for handling requests and database for the backend. BcryptJS for authentication.
- Built RESTful APIs in JavaScript and Express.
- NodeMailer to send a password reset link via email.
- Amazon S3 to host product and collateral images.
- Incorporated responsive design.

EXPERIENCE

Accenture Flex - Digital Media Support Specialist Oct 2019 - Present Denver. CO

- Address Zendesk tickets to provide pre- and post-sales support for Accenture client's (Snap) self-service product (Snapchat advertising platform).
- Streamline support ticket response process with modularized workflow.

IKEA - Prep & Flow

Aug 2019 - Oct 2019

Centennial, CO

- Mastered mobile technology to determine product floor locations and process products for warehouse assignment.
- Created work processes that resulted in a daily completion rate of 100%.

CHRISTIAN ANDERSON, MBA

EXPERIENCE

PRO, IS Inc. - Underwriting Assistant York, PA

May - Oct 2018

- Reviewed accounts to ensure adherence to quality standards.
- Leveraged technology to surpass weekly production goals.

United States Postal Service - Mail Processing Clerk Nov 2016 - Oct 2017 Boulder, CO

- Managed ever-changing priorities daily.
- At the peak of the holiday season, leveraged team personnel to increase package sortation efficiency by 25%.

Penamora Photo - Freelance Photographer

Jul 2012 - Nov 2016

- Westminster, CO
 - Continually interacted with customers to understand their needs and desires. I utilized these stories to streamline my work processes and adjust my product offerings.
 - Processed and cataloged digital images with Adobe Photoshop and Lightroom.

BP - Financial Analyst

May 2001 - Feb 2012

Anchorage, AK

- Organized and coordinated department's close process, resulting in an average of 20% reduction in time spent on close.
- · Mentored finance and engineering staff.
- Through continued study and work outcomes, became 1 of 7 employees designated as a subject matter expert in the finance elements of estimation and categorization of reserves and resources.